Ife Babatunde: All right, so thank you so much, Dr. McCarthy, for taking the time this morning. So as kind of what the materials that have been shared, we're kind of going to be talking about this, AAP Equity Conscious Decision Making, roadmap. We're calling it a roadmap.
Ife Babatunde: We started out as this extensive framework, but we have done a lot of work to refine it.
Ife Babatunde: We had a first phase of, kind of testing amongst, AAP key interest holders to see, you know, what could we do to refine things and get it to a package that could be usable. So we went through an extensive process of weeks of going through and making sure we could, produce this
Ife Babatunde: roadmap that would guide anyone going along that journey of policy development over at AAP. And so, that is kind of what you got in the email.
Ife Babatunde: So now what we're doing is just to see kind of where we're at with it, and see how ready it is to, you know, go out into, the AAP ecosystem. And so we really, value some of the responses that you've provided in the survey.
Ife Babatunde: And a lot of this interview is going to focus on kind of understanding some more about that.
Ife Babatunde: and some things that were not even there. We're also interested in getting some of your opinions on how you think this can be implemented at AAP. You know, some of the pieces that you think might be important.
Ife Babatunde: And some of the ways of even socializing it, over at AAP, even as we're looking to kind of finalize the project and, see this come to life.
Carolyn McCarty: Yeah.
Ife Babatunde: Over at AAP.
Ife Babatunde: Okay. So, I'll go ahead and introduce myself. So, I'm Ife. I'm a PhD student at Case Western Reserve University. So I've been working under the amazing mentorship of Rebecca Morgan over the last couple of years, and this has taken a big… this is a big part of my dissertation project, so I'm looking forward to kind of wrapping up and, getting out there into the real world.
Ife Babatunde: And then, also.
Ife Babatunde: We've been working on this project. There are other team members. I have Michelle, who is also, who also works with Rebecca Morgan, all of us at Evidence Foundation. And I have some of the responses that you gave us, but I wouldn't mind if you could also kind of just introduce yourself and tell us about, kind of, the work that you do.
Carolyn McCarty: Sure, sure. So, I currently work on our guideline development team, also work, with
Carolyn McCarty: Michelle, and I think you're an author on some of our stuff, too. You probably have seen emails from me, and Rebecca, and Room, and the whole team. So I kind of oversee our guideline development process now, but that…
Carolyn McCarty: I've been in this role about 6 months, so I missed the whole first part of this, so it…
Carolyn McCarty: some of the feedback you… I provided in the survey is in part because this is my first time seeing it.
Carolyn McCarty: I had not seen it before. So before that, I was involved in AEP policy development in many ways, but not in our guideline development process.
Carolyn McCarty: so, I think… I think that's probably the most helpful context of who I am for this, yeah.
Ife Babatunde: Absolutely. And have you done any kind of, like, equity work, or have you… do you have any familiarity regarding just even the concept of equity in guideline or guidance development?
Carolyn McCarty: Yeah, so, I mean, I think, yes.
Carolyn McCarty: Broadly, I have, like, my academic background is in disability studies, which is a socio-political look at disability as a construct, and so lots of equity work related to that, lots of, like, community-based equity work. And then…
Carolyn McCarty: as a part of the Academy, kind of equity in all of the work that we do in our policy development, and in the past 6 months, I guess, as that relates to CPG development.
Carolyn McCarty: I would not in any way call myself an equity expert, but certainly familiar with the concepts and kind of committed to the integration of those concepts into the work.
Ife Babatunde: Absolutely. And something that I have loved doing, even during the first phase, and now it's kind of like seeing, you know, are there any examples of,
Ife Babatunde: I guess the importance of incorporating equity, or… So, I guess this is a two-part question. You know, when you think about incorporating equity into guidance development, or guideline development, what does your mind go to?
Ife Babatunde: And are there any examples that you can think of, in your work that just pinpoint it for you? I think some of the, you know, work you described in disability, that's very practical as well, you know, you can't think of that without knowing, yeah, this is an equity-relevant population.
Ife Babatunde: But is there anything that comes to your mind when you think.
Ife Babatunde: Equity Integration and Guideline Development, and any examples that make this relevant for you?
Carolyn McCarty: So, to the first question of, like, what comes to mind, I think the two things…
Carolyn McCarty: that my mind goes to when I think about equity and guidance development is,
Carolyn McCarty: I think primarily concept-wise, my brain goes towards, like, access to healthcare. That's the, like, equity kind of related concept that I…
Carolyn McCarty: probably focus on when I think about equity in, like, the implementation of the guideline.
Carolyn McCarty: And how that impacts the development of the recommendations.
Carolyn McCarty: I think the other, like, part of the process that…
Carolyn McCarty: I don't know, the other thing that my mind is going towards is, like, the makeup of the panel and the stakeholders involved in the guidance development.
Carolyn McCarty: And that feels… broader… To me, as well, like…
Carolyn McCarty: I guess an example of why that feels, like, broader and complex in this moment is that we're… we have a guideline on urinary tract infections. I think you're involved in that.
Carolyn McCarty: And… and there are tensions, related to…
Carolyn McCarty: like, the type of provider who's… their view and perceptions of the work. And so, I don't know where and how that fits in, but that feels like a layer
Carolyn McCarty: of how to think about the makeup of the panel. It has some… parallels, or… egg.
Carolyn McCarty: draws into the equity work some, too. So, like, who they are, who they represent, what they know, like, their expertise, but also, like, who they're representing in many ways.
Carolyn McCarty: Feels.
Carolyn McCarty: like, something my brain gets pulled towards when I think about equity and guidance.
Ife Babatunde: Absolutely, absolutely. Which actually would… it kind of even highlights one of the sections in the framework, which is…
Ife Babatunde: that, you know, guideline group, membership, and, I'm… that was kind of one of… I actually did notice kind of the responses you gave in that section as well, so, I think that's… it's good to know that, you know, some part of that framework,
Ife Babatunde: did look relevant,
Ife Babatunde: to the work that you're doing, so thank you very much for that. So, you know, before I get in, like I said, we started off with this really extensive framework. We conducted a scoping review and went into the literature to kind of find, different organizational frameworks on equity integration.
Ife Babatunde: And then, I think at the first phase, we had this extensive document, where we synthesized our findings, and tried to pull different elements that would be relevant, for any aspect of guideline or guidance creation.
Ife Babatunde: We ended up with, like, a 50-page document, which, you know, during the first phase, there was a lot of feedback as to, you know, the comprehensiveness of it, the clarity, language, terminology, and just that overall snapshot. How do we even use this?
Ife Babatunde: How do we tie this into AAP and the processes we have going on here? And so we took that feedback, and we have come up with
Ife Babatunde: two different things. So, the first thing was the visual that we have. Right now is kind of different from what the original visual was, which was… now our approach was to go into the AAP process, and so we worked with, some of the people, leadership on the project to kind of figure out, okay, what are the steps that AAP guidance development goes through?
Ife Babatunde: And taking some of that, process, the outlined process and procedure that was given to us, how do we now tie in, the framework that we initially had? And so, we were able to kind of divide the different, the three, the 18 different sections we had of the framework, or we ended up with of the framework, into those three big buckets.
Ife Babatunde: Going from, you know, that intent process all the way to the executive review.
Ife Babatunde: And just you looking at that, did you have any feedback, about what that represented, and anything that, would be useful for us to take into consideration?
Ife Babatunde: I guess, you know, how did… how much did you like it? How useful do you think it would be, and what might be beneficial?
Carolyn McCarty: Yeah, so I… Did not spend a ton of time thinking about
Carolyn McCarty: the visual itself. I did look at it and thought it was helpful, but didn't
Carolyn McCarty: like, review it, if that makes sense.
Carolyn McCarty: I think… and I don't… so I don't know what level of, like, thought or detail you want on this. Like, the… for example, AAP policy has an intent process. Our clinical practice guidelines
Carolyn McCarty: currently don't… we don't call it an intent. I don't know if that matters. We all know what that means, but I don't know how much that matters.
Carolyn McCarty: Here, I think… so that jumped out at me. I knew what it meant. It doesn't… anyways.
Carolyn McCarty: I think… I don't know, I'd have to look at it more closely, I think, to think about
Carolyn McCarty: anything more specific? I think it's helpful to bucket…
Carolyn McCarty: stuff into kind of, like, what phase are we talking about? I think the other thing that I'm wondering, and I don't have solid thoughts on this right now, I'm happy to at some point if it's helpful, but is there something in between the intent and the writing?
Carolyn McCarty: like, are there some pieces that are currently in intent that are in it… there's an in-between phase, or are actually in the writing, what we're calling the writing phase? And I'd have to think more about that to…
Carolyn McCarty: Like, question generation, for example.
Carolyn McCarty: I just wonder if that naturally fits under a tent, or writing, or something in between.
Carolyn McCarty: The two of them.
Carolyn McCarty: Import… the last one, importance of outcomes, interventions, values, and preferences. Like, thinking about our own process.
Carolyn McCarty: What we call intent is really, like, the initial proposal, and those things are not done in them.
Carolyn McCarty: face.
Ife Babatunde: Okay, I think that's very useful feedback for us, because, the understanding we were given was that all different policies, so clinical practice guidelines.
Ife Babatunde: The clinical, guidance, the clinical reports and the policy reports all go through that high-level
Ife Babatunde: three phases. So if there's something different that CPGs go through, you know, we'll be very happy to incorporate that. Okay. Yeah.
Carolyn McCarty: Yeah, so, okay, I'll just give the caveat again, I'm just 6 months in, but I do think that
Carolyn McCarty: there is a very concrete intent process for policy statements, clinical reports, and technical reports. The approval process, which is the parallel of the intent process for the CPGs, is just a little bit different, and how relevant that is to
Carolyn McCarty: display here, I think, could be up for debate.
Carolyn McCarty: Yep.
Ife Babatunde: Is there… is there something, maybe, that outlines what this looks like that you could maybe share via email that we could look at? That would be very helpful for our team.
Carolyn McCarty: Yeah,
Carolyn McCarty: Let me follow… yeah, let me see what we have, and again, follow up on… I might… is it okay? I know… so I know you're interviewing… well, you will interview Lauren Pilcher at some point. She is also on my team. Is it okay if we, like, talk and send over
Carolyn McCarty: Something to you.
Ife Babatunde: Absolutely, absolutely.
Ife Babatunde: Absolutely, yeah, because, you know, like I said, we, when we, kind of asked questions, from Melissa, who we've been in contact with about this, you know, the idea we were given was, like, all of them. I think she had to clarify for CPGs, but what the feedback we ended up getting was that they all go through
Ife Babatunde: That 3-step…
Ife Babatunde: three phases, which was why we ended up just mapping everything, and we want to make sure that the roadmap is applicable, not just to the clinical reports, but to also the CPGs, you know.
Ife Babatunde: So, if there's a way we can, you know, we would be very happy to kind of incorporate, things that are relevant in that phase, just to make sure that someone who is working on a CPG can look at it and be like, oh, okay, I know where to go when I'm here and there, or at this point in the process.
Carolyn McCarty: Okay, okay, I'm happy to look at it more in detail and think with Lauren or someone else on the team about what,
Carolyn McCarty: best represents the CPGs here, and share that back with you.
Ife Babatunde: Okay, sounds good. Thank you so much.
Carolyn McCarty: Yeah, yeah.
Ife Babatunde: Okay, so that kind of leads us into kind of the survey and some of the responses that was given. So, I mentioned that when we did the initial review and refinement, we did for comprehensive… comprehensiveness, clarity of language, and, conciseness.
Ife Babatunde: And we wanted it to be relevant. So…
Ife Babatunde: most of the questions, when you were reviewing the sections, they had those three questions. Is this comprehensive? Is this relevant? Is the language… are the terminologies here clear? So…
Ife Babatunde: you know, we… I got the, kind of, the feedback, and you had very consistent feedback across, and I think the first thing that kind of jumped out was when, of those three different things that we were aiming to do, the ratings around the language and terminology
Ife Babatunde: for the framework or for the roadmap was mostly consistent around neutral.
Ife Babatunde: And I wanted to kind of ask, some of the rationale behind that, because… just because it appeared in the different sections, and we can go into very specific sections later for other ones, but that was one that I felt was pretty consistent throughout your responses.
Carolyn McCarty: Yeah, I think my… high-level thought, and this may…
Carolyn McCarty: be related to the purpose, but was that… I think it's great. I think that…
Carolyn McCarty: There is language in it that will be
Carolyn McCarty: difficult for a user to operationalize, so to take it from a roadmap to actually using it. And so, that is… that is, I think, what you see likely reflected in most of my feedback, is…
Carolyn McCarty: this feels like a great concept. As a guideline, someone who helps develop guidelines, I don't…
Carolyn McCarty: And someone with some familiarity, really a decent amount of familiarity with equity, but that it's not my full job
Carolyn McCarty: I don't know how to take that from, like, that's a great idea, to here's what I'm gonna do about it.
Carolyn McCarty: And that was my challenge, and so that's what… when I was thinking about language.
Carolyn McCarty: etc. Like, that's what I was thinking about, and that's likely what you see reflected in the writings and the comments.
Carolyn McCarty: Primarily.
Ife Babatunde: Okay, and I think that's very helpful. So, two things. The first thing is, when you say, difficult for a user, when you're thinking of a user, are you thinking of someone in your role, or what kind of roles,
Ife Babatunde: Define user in your mind, when you think of someone.
Carolyn McCarty: Yeah, that's a great question. So, I mean, primarily me, or someone like me, who is,
Carolyn McCarty: thinking about how to implement the process of developing a guideline, how to, like, guide a group through developing a guideline, because it does feel like
Carolyn McCarty: My job to know…
Carolyn McCarty: here is how I need to take that guidance and operationalize it into how to help a group do this thing that it's supposed to be doing.
Carolyn McCarty: So, that's really who I was thinking about, mostly.
Ife Babatunde: Okay, so, and that's good, a very important role, someone who's guiding a group, who's overseeing, you know, the project, project management and things like that. So what kind of additional guidance would you say would be helpful
Ife Babatunde: For someone in your role, if they're looking at the roadmap, you can take any section, or any, any of them, and just say, okay, this is something that would be helpful for me here, or if something is worded, or if something is added, you know, any additions, any word-ins, whatever it is, what do you think, or even an additional guide, whatever you think might be helpful.
Ife Babatunde: What do you… what would be relevant here?
Carolyn McCarty: Yeah, so I think I tried in the feedback to flag for each one. I think for some of them.
Carolyn McCarty: it's as simple as, like, an example. Here's an example of what that could look like, even if there's… like, even… maybe that's just a phrase of, like, this could be a…
Carolyn McCarty: What if it's, like, a group of, like.
Carolyn McCarty: if there are multiple ways to achieve whatever it is, like, here's an example of what that could be.
Carolyn McCarty: Or if there's something you can link to as an example of how somebody else did it, whatever that guidance step was, I think is good.
Carolyn McCarty: I think… I'm trying to reflect on specific ones, but I think a lot of them examples would be helpful. I think there were likely some that I felt like
Carolyn McCarty: an additional… which, I don't know that this is your top, but, like, in follow-up to this, maybe, like, an additional guidance tool that is, like, this is how you…
Carolyn McCarty: Think about this bigger concept, and the steps it might look like to implement this bigger concept could be helpful.
Ife Babatunde: Okay, yeah, that's very helpful. So we have been also trying to, kind of develop what we're calling
Ife Babatunde: an operationalization guide.
Carolyn McCarty: Yeah.
Ife Babatunde: Pretty much. It's almost like a… it's very, kind of, in a rough stage right now, but it's like a list of do's and don'ts.
Ife Babatunde: To a company. And so it kind of carries a lot of, like, general concepts. So, like, oh, use a flow chart, you know, to represent, maybe, kind of equity, or, like, you know, provide some supports.
Ife Babatunde: or, resources for peer review. But a lot of it is kind of, I guess.
Ife Babatunde: open for, what'd I say.
Ife Babatunde: I guess, feedback on what is really relevant. So, we don't want to put out something that's generic, but something that's relevant to AAP. So do you think, like, an operationalization guide
Ife Babatunde: Would be helpful, or… and also, when you think of, do's and don'ts.
Ife Babatunde: you think examples along with those dues would… it would be what would make them more concrete, or, you know, is that something that you think, you know, this is really kind of like an internal AAP
Ife Babatunde: project or thing to do. What would you say?
Carolyn McCarty: Yes, I think in oper… operationalization, guys.
Carolyn McCarty: Helpful, and yes, my perception is that examples are really helpful. I think, I mean, you likely know this, there are so many, like, concepts
Carolyn McCarty: And words, these, like, weighty words in equity work that…
Carolyn McCarty: Have a lot of meaning to them that may not always carry that same meaning with the person reading it, or you may not…
Carolyn McCarty: Know the full meaning of that concept, and so,
Carolyn McCarty: I think where we can bring those things to life is really helpful.
Ife Babatunde: Absolutely, absolutely. So, Justin…
Ife Babatunde: still reviewing some of the sections from your survey responses. There was a part, so when Section 9, the considering the importance of outcomes Interventions.
Ife Babatunde: Values, preferences, and use, utilities.
Ife Babatunde: There was some kind of… there was a comment you had left about providing guidance
Ife Babatunde: On what to do if you don't find published literature on patient values. Is this something that you've encountered in the past before?
Carolyn McCarty: my experience is limited. So, no.
Carolyn McCarty: I can't think of a specific place that I've encountered that, but I, believe that I have heard that that is not uncommon, that there's, it's relatively common to not be able to find the published.
Carolyn McCarty: literature on it, and so I just… I think that one specifically, I noticed that there was guidance to do it, to search for it, and then I was like, okay, but what?
Ife Babatunde: Whatever you get, David, what do you do?
Carolyn McCarty: Because it feels important, right? It feels important to understand that, and one way to understand it is the search literature, but if it's not there, how do you understand it?
Ife Babatunde: Hmm. Okay, absolutely. Okay.
Ife Babatunde: So I'm looking… Alright, so there were some other comments you had made in different sections about
Ife Babatunde: kind of moving things maybe from one section, moving them up in the framework, and things like that. And, then there was, I think, there were two sections, so in the reporting and peer review section.
Ife Babatunde: and in the dissemination and implementation section. Those two sections, you kind of disagreed with them being comprehensive enough.
Ife Babatunde: And so I wanted to kind of understand, for those two sections, we can start with the reporting and, peer review on kind of, you know, what would be… what would you be looking to see here? What would be beneficial?
Carolyn McCarty: Wow.
Carolyn McCarty: I need to read it again.
Carolyn McCarty: And I need to remind myself.
Carolyn McCarty: I think I… the word reporting also took me a minute to understand what concepts that I'm just.
Carolyn McCarty: Looking back at the glossary.
Carolyn McCarty: Oh, it's made public.
Carolyn McCarty: Okay, so I think, in terms of peer review, I can't remember if I wrote this anywhere or not, like.
Carolyn McCarty: the consideration of who should be reviewing, and how it's made available for peer review, I think are two…
Carolyn McCarty: Two pieces that felt relevant to me.
Carolyn McCarty: As it relates to equity.
Ife Babatunde: Okay.
Carolyn McCarty: that I didn't… Feel like we're represented.
Carolyn McCarty: At least not in that section.
Carolyn McCarty: And then… Also, for the reporting piece,
Carolyn McCarty: like, who…
Carolyn McCarty: who it intentionally gets pushed to, like, who we're making sure… I guess that's probably in dissemination and implementation, honestly, and maybe that's there, so…
Carolyn McCarty: pause on that thought. I can't think of specific thoughts I had about the reporting piece.
Ife Babatunde: There was a comment you had left… there was a comment you left about, guidance on how to support diverse review viewpoints. Yeah. Yeah, so is that what you're kind of referring to when you say who is reviewing and…
Carolyn McCarty: Yeah.
Ife Babatunde: Okay, yeah, could you… could you speak on that just a little bit more? Because I had made a note to kind of hear a little bit more as to kind of what you're referring to, with that.
Carolyn McCarty: So…
Carolyn McCarty: Our process at the Academy is that we handpick, kind of, which internal groups and which external groups have the opportunity to review. And so…
Carolyn McCarty: I think in… when we are making those lists, really being thoughtful about, what are the groups. Like, what…
Carolyn McCarty: equity considerations do we need to have in mind as we think about who we're inviting to review the guideline? Like, it's not an open comment, it's not, like, made available to the community to comment on it.
Carolyn McCarty: So… just being really, I think, thoughtful there, what patient groups need to be represented in that,
Carolyn McCarty: We think a lot about what
Carolyn McCarty: professional groups need to be represented, but I think also thinking about what groups can we access that represent the patients impacted by this. I don't know, I just think there's…
Carolyn McCarty: Alright, that's kind of what I was thinking.
Ife Babatunde: Okay.
Ife Babatunde: Yeah, that makes sense. And also,
Ife Babatunde: I guess something similar with the, dissemination and implementation section,
Ife Babatunde: How would you comment on, you know, what might be missing, or…
Ife Babatunde: Because that was also another section where you disagreed with comprehensiveness.
Carolyn McCarty: Okay, give me a second.
Ife Babatunde: Hmm.
Ife Babatunde: And then I also… I can… I can read out some of the things you had written.
Carolyn McCarty: Okay, yes.
Ife Babatunde: That would be helpful. Sure. So I know for specific points, so points one, you felt like that should have been.
Ife Babatunde: At an earlier stage, versus in dissemination and implementation. 4.6, you agreed with, the efforts that were listed there, but you also kind of…
Ife Babatunde: Suggested moving, removing, or drawing some kind of connection for the reader or the, user.
Ife Babatunde: you wanted a little bit more elaboration on point 8, what results are we talking about in there? And then, you know, just spelling out some of the abbreviations, GDG, for example, and what that would stand for. So those were some of the, rewarding suggestions you had.
Ife Babatunde: But… What other things would kind of encompass your, rating, disagreeing with comprehensiveness for this?
Carolyn McCarty: Huh.
Carolyn McCarty: Thank you, that was helpful to remind me of my thoughts.
Carolyn McCarty: Okay, I'm trying to read through it, but I think… That… the…
Carolyn McCarty: as I'm reading it and trying to think back on my thoughts and…
Carolyn McCarty: That the… it's the dissemination piece that maybe felt a little…
Carolyn McCarty: less represented, in this section, and maybe that goes back to the point I started to make under the reporting and peer review, but just kind of who we
Carolyn McCarty: Want to make sure
Carolyn McCarty: Has… knows that it was published, knows that it's available, knows what the key points are.
Carolyn McCarty: Even prior to trying to implement it, but just the, like, kind of getting the word out piece of…
Carolyn McCarty: That it was done.
Carolyn McCarty: I think I… you could totally point to something that says I'm wrong, but that… that is not…
Carolyn McCarty: Jumping out at me in that list right now.
Ife Babatunde: Absolutely, absolutely. Okay, so those are majority of, kind of, the, responses we wanted to elaborate a bit on. Okay. So if we were to, kind of, just even leave, kind of, just the survey responses and go to any other comments
Ife Babatunde: specifically on the roadmap as is, that you wanted to kind of highlight for us, even as we continue to work on this, what would those be?
Carolyn McCarty: Yeah, I think we've… Talked about it, really.
Carolyn McCarty: the two main things that I felt were support and operationalizing some of these.
Carolyn McCarty: concepts, and just the… that there are some things that I think are…
Carolyn McCarty: could be placed in a different section so that they're considered at a different point in the process.
Carolyn McCarty: I think those were my two main things that I walked away.
Carolyn McCarty: thinking about. I think that the definitions at the top are really helpful,
Carolyn McCarty: because I certainly had to reference them, I like that you have those. I will, talk internally about the
Carolyn McCarty: roadmap, and if there's anything about CPGs that might look different that could be helpful to reflect.
Carolyn McCarty: But in terms of the, kind of, sections and elements themselves, those were the big things.
Ife Babatunde: Okay.
Carolyn McCarty: that I… thought about.
Ife Babatunde: Okay, that's, that's really helpful.
Ife Babatunde: And we would definitely kind of take all of these into consideration. One step that would be coming up, after we have finalized and refined, after this phase of, kind of, testing and validation, we would also have this socialization, piece of the framework.
Ife Babatunde: And one thing that we want to do there is, you know, introducing it to AAP. And so, one question I did have about that is, what would you think would be helpful, what would be a helpful method?
Ife Babatunde: Or how do you think it might look like for this framework to be introduced, within AAP to different users and to people who kind of work within the guideline development, sector?
Carolyn McCarty: Yeah. So I don't know that this is…
Carolyn McCarty: your role or thing that you have to think about, but I think the main thing as an academy staff person reading this that I wondered is, like.
Carolyn McCarty: What of this?
Carolyn McCarty: when it's rolled out is expectation now. Like, this is what you will do, and what of this is,
Carolyn McCarty: kind of helpful to think about, considerations to have. So in terms of, like, implementing within our organization, just being… I think it will be helpful for us as staff who do the work to be clear on
Carolyn McCarty: Like, is this our new process? Is this our new… expectations.
Carolyn McCarty: Or what of it is, or…
Carolyn McCarty: obviously, not at all. It's always the expectation to consider equity, but now that we have specific things, like, which of these specific things, or all of them, are…
Ife Babatunde: food.
Carolyn McCarty: To be implemented each time.
Ife Babatunde: Yeah, I think that's… that's a very interesting and important point, you know, expectation versus consideration. And kind of…
Ife Babatunde: considering, kind of, the process at AAP, maybe whatever it is that is already being done regarding equity, or just even in the procedure for developing any type of policy.
Ife Babatunde: Do you think it,
Ife Babatunde: having more considerations or concrete expectations might be beneficial or burdensome, to the end users. What do you think would be more clear-cut, and what do you think would kind of be,
Ife Babatunde: Easier to integrate, as you, kind of, into your work as it is currently.
Carolyn McCarty: Yeah, I mean, I think… where…
Carolyn McCarty: There are expectations, it being clear that those are expectations.
Carolyn McCarty: is helpful.
Carolyn McCarty: And where we are just… they're wanting us to encourage, you know, kind of additional ways of integrating equity, it's helpful to know that. One thing that's
Carolyn McCarty: Coming to mind for me, is this will exist in…
Carolyn McCarty: Well, it feels like, right now, it will exist in parallel to our, kind of.
Carolyn McCarty: Existing and what's being generated, like, policy guidance.
Carolyn McCarty: And I wonder…
Carolyn McCarty: where there may be opportunity to really bring the two together. So there's a whole group of people working on laying out our policy process, our policy development process, and they've got this whole series of steps and stages that they're developing in parallel to y'all doing this work.
Carolyn McCarty: It feels to me like it could be really helpful for those to intersect at some point and say, in this policy process, here now is where you integrate this equity step, and here is where you integrate this equity step, so that it's not…
Carolyn McCarty: As the staff, we're not having to kind of look in two different places to guide us and assess.
Ife Babatunde: Oh, that's very good to know, and I think it's something we probably would have to bring up with the leadership about this, because it would be, you know, less burdensome for things to be more integrated together versus, you know, two separate guidance.
Carolyn McCarty: Yeah, yeah. And I think it just helps. We all want to do work that is more equitable. No, literally nobody at the academy doesn't want to do that. You wouldn't be.
Carolyn McCarty: And so it just helps us to do that. It helps us to bring
Carolyn McCarty: it kind of always to the forefront of our mind as we're doing each stage of these processes that are really kind of rigid and laid out. For us, our policy development process is that
Carolyn McCarty: rigid, kind of diagnosed approach. And so to, like, work this in, to that, I think, well…
Carolyn McCarty: Help in implementation.
Carolyn McCarty: Of the cadets.
Ife Babatunde: Absolutely, absolutely. Well, I'm… I think that's pretty much all the questions I had, and these were all wonderful responses, so I just really want to thank you for taking the time, to talk to me. So, in the last 3 minutes, are there any kind of questions you have for me, or anything you want me… any notes you want me to make?
Ife Babatunde: Even as we kind of round up this interview?
Carolyn McCarty: I don't think so. I think it's really important work. I'm glad that we're doing it, and thank you for leading through it. I think it's great, and I look forward to getting to use it in our work of guideline development.
Carolyn McCarty: Yeah, and the more…
Carolyn McCarty: I don't want to say hand-holding, but a little bit, like, the more that we can be given really concrete
Carolyn McCarty: things to do. I know we don't want to have
Carolyn McCarty: checklists, I know we don't want it to just be, like, a thing that you do in checkup, and also having concrete steps is…
Carolyn McCarty: helpful in implementing and integrating things into a complex process that already exists. So, the more we can do that in a way that doesn't take away from the spirit of just, like, integrating equity
Carolyn McCarty: it's helpful, so…
Ife Babatunde: Absolutely, absolutely. And thank you, and we're really excited to kind of have this ready to share with, you all at AAP, so thank you so much for your input, and for all of your responses. They have been very well noted.
Ife Babatunde: Thank you.
Carolyn McCarty: Well, thanks for your work, appreciate it.
Ife Babatunde: Thank you so much, Dr. McCarty. I hope you have a lovely rest of your day.
Carolyn McCarty: Yes, you too. Alright, bye. Bye, Michelle.
Michelle Watson: Bye.
Ife Babatunde: Okay, Michelle, I'm gonna stop recording.